Guide to the American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1899-2008.
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1899-2008.
6578
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences.
351.4 cubic feet
Correspondence, subject files, publications, photographs, audiotapes, videotapes, scrapbooks, memorabilia, and artifacts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, minutes, resolutions, bylaws, publications, and correspondence, pertaining to the history of the association; membership lists, planning guides, national records, handbooks, public relations material, Board of Directors records, newsletters, programs, annual reports, photographs, video- and audiotapes, and records of the International Federation for Home Economics. Includes records concerning the history of home economics, families, youth, consumer education, the International Family Planning Project, public policy, and nutrition.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences was founded in 1909 as the American Home Economics Association. The Association had its origins in the Lake Placid Conferences that were held from 1899 to 1908 with the aim of becoming “a kind of clearinghouse for all the schools and teachers of home economics.” They hoped their audience would include the “professional worker in the home and institutional household, and all, whether students, scientists, or practical persons, who are interested in the improvement of living conditions.” The conferences were first convened by Ellen Richards and others interested in the emerging field of home economics. Ellen Richards is considered to be the founder of the American Home Economics Association and was a pioneer in home economics as a field of scientific study and social reform. The involvement of these early professional home economists in sanitation and public health, child development, scientific nutrition, functional home and environmental design, education, and household management set the stage for the endeavors of professional home economists in the following years.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports, minutes, resolutions, bylaws, publications, and correspondence, pertaining to the history of the association; membership lists, planning guides, national records, handbooks, public relations material, Board of Directors records, newsletters, programs, annual reports, photographs, video and audio tapes, and records of the International Federation for Home Economics. Includes records concerning the history of home economics, families, youth, consumer education, the International Family Planning Project, public policy, and nutrition.
SUBJECTS
Names:
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences.; American Home Economics Association.; International Family Planning Project.
Subjects:
Home economists--United States; Women's rights.; Women--Social conditions.; Women--Education.; Home economics--Congresses.; Youth--United States.; Home economists--United States--Directories.; Consumer education--United States.; Nutrition--Study and teaching--United States.; Women reformers.; Home economics--United States--History--20th century.; Home economics--Study and teaching--United States.; Family life education--United States--History.; Home economics teachers--Training of--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.; Audiotapes.; Computer discs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 124, 125 and folders 31 and 32 of box 308 are closed to the public. The presence of names of members of AAFCS may be verified by an archivist.
The files of the AHEA Foundation are restricted for 50 years from date of creation except with the permission of the AAFCS Board of Directors. Permission would be obtained through a written request to the Board.
RELATED MATERIALS
International Federation for Home Economics-United States records, 1977-2003. #6760.
New York State Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1908-2005. #3410.
Benjamin Andrews collection on home economics, 1879-1958. #1475
Marie Dye collection on the University of Chicago, 1919-1972. #6759.
Marjorie Knoll papers, 1954-1999. #6787.
Family and Consumer Sciences administrators study records, 1995-1996. #6704.
Pundt, Helen. AHEA, a history of excellence. Washington, D.C.: American Home Economics Association, c1980.
Baldwin, Keturah E. 1879- The AHEA saga: a brief history of the origin and development of the American Home Economics Association and a glimpse at the grass roots from which it grew. Washington: American Home Economics Association, [1949]
SERIES LIST
Series I. Governance
Executive Groups and Boards
Officers
Past Presidents
Council
Assembly of Delegates
Senate
Elections
Annual Reports
Bylaws
Directories and policy handbooks
Resolutions
Series II. Administration
Accreditation
AHEA Foundation
Awards, Scholarships and Fellowships
Center for the Family
Certification
Consumer Interests and Standards
Correspondence and Subject Files
Field Service
International Activities
Library and Archives
Membership
National Headquarters Staff and Operations
Outside Organizations
Program Division
Projects and Programs
Public Policy
Public Relations
Publications and Publishing
Series III. Annual Meetings and Conferences
Lake Placid Conferences
Eleventh Lake Placid Conference
Annual Meeting Programs
Series IV. Committees
Series V. Professional and Subject-Matter Groups
Series VI. State Associations
Series VII. Biographical Files
Series VIII. Photographs and Slides
Series IX. Audiotapes, Videotapes, LPs, CDs, and Motion Picture Film
Series X. Memorabilia and Artifacts
Series XI. Publications
Series XII. Ellen H. Richards
Series XIII. Home Economics History
Series XIV. Addition to Collection (2014-2017)
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Governance
  This series contains the records of the governing bodies of the Association and is divided into 11 subseries based on the type of governing group or type of record.
  - Executive groups and boards
    This series contains records of the various executive groups and boards of the Association. They are listed generally in chronological order.
    - Minutes, correspondence, reports, 1908-1919; 5 folders (Box 158)
    - Minutes copies with Benjamin Andrews' signature, 1909-1915 (Box 109)
    - AHEA Administrative Records, Volume 1, 1908-1919; 2 folders (Box 158)
    - Executive minutes and correspondence, 1910-1912, 1919-1927; 5 folders (Box 158)
    - Executive minutes and correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 117)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1913, 1921-1923, 1927-1929 (Box 117)
    - Executive Committee, 1922, 1931, 1935 (Box 117)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1930-1939 (Box 117)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1930-1937; 8 folders (Box 117)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee minutes and correspondence, 1932-1953 (Box 117)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee minutes and correspondence, 1932-1953; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee meetings, 1936-1939; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1940-1949 (Box 10)
    - Executive Board, Executive Committee, and Council minutes and reports, 1940-1959 (Box 10)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1941-1949 (Box 10)
    - Executive Board, 1942-1949 (Box 10)
    - Wartime Institute: program, handouts, 1943 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee, 1943-1949 (Box 10)
    - Board and Committee meeting minutes, reports, summary reports from Departments and Divisions, circa 1940-1960; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee, Executive Board meeting minutes and correspondence, 1945-1950 (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1946-1950 (Box 105)
    - Council, Executive Board/Executive Committee, 1946-1956; 3 folders (Box 105)
    - Executive Board materials, 1949-1953 (Box 105)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee, 1949-1953 (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee, 1950-1954, 1965 (Box 105)
    - Executive Board, 1950-1956 (Box 105)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1950-1959 (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee/Executive Board annual meeting, 1950-1957; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1950-1959 (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee/Executive Board, 1950-1958; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Board of Trustees minutes, 1951; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee, 1954-1958 (Box 105)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee, 1954-1959 (Box 105)
    - Executive Committee/Executive Board, 1957-1961 (Box 105)
    - Board of Trustees, Board of Directors, Executive Board, 1958-1960 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board and Executive Committee minutes, 1959-1962 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee/Assembly of Delegates, 1960-1962 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee/Executive Board, 1960-1962 (Box 269)
    - Board of Trustees, Board of Directors, Executive Board, 1961-1963 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1960-1967 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1960-1968 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board/Executive Committee/Assembly of Delegates, 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 269)
    - Executive Board, 1961 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board/Board of Directors minutes, 1960-1968; 9 folders (Box 269)
    - Minutes book, 1962-1965; 2 folders (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee, Executive Board, Board of Trustees, Assembly of Delegates, 1964-1965 (Box 269)
    - Executive Board, 1964 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1965 (Box 269)
    - Board of Trustees agenda and minutes, 1965 (Box 269)
    - Preconvention meeting minutes of the Executive Board, 1965 (Box 269)
    - Meeting minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1965 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee Meeting, 1965 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee minutes and agenda, 1965-1966 (Box 269)
    - Board of Trustees agenda, 1966 (Box 269)
    - Executive Committee, Executive Board, Board of Trustees, Assembly of Delegates, 1966-1968 (Box 269)
    - Board of Directors, Executive Committee meeting materials, 1966-1969; 4 folders (Box 269)
    - Minutes, Board of Directors, Executive Committee, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 269)
    - Board of Directors minutes, 1969-1973 (Box 269)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1964, 1966-1977; 25 folders (Box 246)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1971 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1970-1971 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1971 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1971-1973 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 68)
    - Executive Board/Board of Directors minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 68)
    - Follow-up of Board of Directors meeting, 1975-01 (Box 68)
    - Pre-convention Board meeting, 1975-06 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors Vote Union Trust resolution, 1975 (Box 68)
    - Board materials, 1976-10 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors, 1976-01 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors information packet, 1976; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 68)
    - Pre-Convention Board meeting, 1977-06 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1977-06 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1977-10 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Post-Convention Board of Directors meeting, 1978-06-30 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1978-01 (Box 68)
    - Board Orientation Workshop, 1978-09 (Box 68)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1977-1981-01; 23 folders (Box 101)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1981-06-1987-01; 28 folders (Box 134)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1982-1983; 8 folders (Box 77)
    - Board of Directors minutes, 1975-1983; 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Program of Work, 1981-1984 (Box 77)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1983; 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Post-Board meeting, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1978-1981; 4 folders (Box 94)
    - Pre-Convention Board of Directors and Assembly minutes, motion cards, 1979 (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1979-1981; 3 folders (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors reports, 1980-1981; 6 folders (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1981; 4 folders (Box 94)
    - Board reports, 1981-06 (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors agendas and meeting materials, 1982 (Box 94)
    - Board briefs, 1982 (Box 94)
    - Post-Convention Board minutes, 1985-06 (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1990-1991; 3 folders (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors, 1994 (Box 94)
    - Governance information, Board of Directors meetings, Assembly of Delegates, Nominating Committee, 1994; 2 folders (Box 94)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1987-01-1989-06; 23 folders (Box 149)
    - Executive Committee conference call, 1989-07 (Box 149)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1989-09-1990-01; 4 folders (Box 149)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1990-01; 3 folders (Box 201)
    - Finance Committee, Board of Directors meetings, 1990-04 (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1990-06-1990-09; 7 folders (Box 201)
    - Finance Committee, Board of Directors meetings, 1990-10-1990-11 (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors meetings and mailings, 1990-1991-06; 8 folders (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1991-06; 5 folders (Box 201)
    - Executive Committee conference call, 1991-07 (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1991-09; 2 folders (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors' reference, governance, and policy materials, 1990-1991; 3 folders (Box 201)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1992-01; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Executive Committee, Finance Committee conference calls, 1992-02-1992-04 (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1992-05-1992-09; 7 folders (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors, Finance Committee, Executive Committee meetings, 1992-07-1992-12 (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1992; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Finance Committee, Board of Directors meetings, 1993-01 (Box 283)
    - Finance Committee, Executive Committee meetings, 1993-03-1993-06 (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1993-06-1993-09; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Finance Committee, Executive Committee, Board of Directors meetings, 1993-10-1993-12 (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors mailings, 1993-1994; 3 folders (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1994-01; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Finance Committee, Executive Committee meetings, 1994-02-1994-06 (Box 283)
    - Board of Directors meeting materials, 1992-01; 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Executive Director's updates to Board of Directors, 1992-1993 (Box 77)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1994-06-1995-09; 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Finance Committee, Executive Committee, Board of Directors meetings, 1994-09 (Box 77)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1995-1999; 21 folders (Box 118)
    - Board of Directors meeting materials, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Board of Directors correspondence, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Budgets, 1995-2001; 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Awards, fellowships and scholarships, 1999-2000 (Box 54)
    - Business Section, 1998; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Correspondence and reports, 2001-2002; 4 folders (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 31)
  - Officers
    There are few records of officers in the AAFCS records. These files largely represent their interactions with the Executive Director and national headquarters.
    - President
      - Kathryn VanAken Burns
        - General correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 118)
        - AHEA history (Box 118)
        - Typescript about Kathryn VanAken Burns (Box 118)
        - Talks and notes (Box 118)
        - Executive Secretary: correspondence, 1936-1938; 2 folders (Box 118)
        - Vocational education, 1937-1938 (Box 118)
        - Minutes- secretary, 1936-1938 (Box 118)
        - Trips and meetings, 1936-1938 (Box 118)
        - Journal editor: correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 118)
      - Jessie Harris: correspondence, 1943 (Box 118)
      - Katharine Alderman: correspondence, 1945-1947; 2 folders (Box 118)
      - Marie Dye: correspondence, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box 118)
      - Florence Fallgatter
        - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 118)
        - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 118)
        - Correspondence to Executive Secretary, 1951-1952 (Box 217)
        - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 217)
      - Elizabeth Sweeney Herbert
        - President-elect, correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 217)
        - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 217)
      - Catherine T. Dennis: correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 217)
      - Beulah Gillaspie, 1956 (Box 217)
      - Olga Brucher
        - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 227)
        - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 227)
        - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 227)
        - Correspondence, 1958-07 (Box 227)
        - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 227)
      - Dorothy Lyle: correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 217)
      - Florence Low: correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 217)
      - Dr. Lela O'Toole: correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 217)
      - Satenig St. Marie: correspondence, reports, speeches, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 217)
      - Satenig St. Marie: Field Service speeches, 1973-1974; Audiocassette tapes (Box 40)
      - Agatha Huepenbecker: correspondence-certification/accreditation, 1987 (Box 227)
    - Vice President
      - Frances Clinton, 1953-1954 (Box 217)
      - Edna A. Hill, 1953-1954 (Box 217)
      - Lela O'Toole-Constitution and Bylaws revisions, 1962 (Box 217)
      - Gwen Lam, 1964 (Box 217)
    - Secretary
      - M. Gertrude Halloway, 1953-1954 (Box 217)
    - Treasurer
      - Marie Mount, 1947 (Box 217)
      - U. Vivian Crow: correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 217)
      - Evalyn Bergstrand Owens, 1953-1954 (Box 217)
    - Officers' Handbooks, circa 1960 (Box 217)
    - Officers' Handbook, 1962-1963 (Box 217)
    - Officers Handbook, circa 1963 (Box 217)
    - Officer and committee lists, 1947-1974 (Box 217)
  - Past Presidents
    This subseries contains information on the Past Presidents' Unit.
    - History of the Past Presidents' Unit (incomplete), 1991 (Box 227)
    - History of the Past Presidents' Unit, 1973; 3 folders (Box 227)
    - Speeches, correspondence, 1994 (Box 227)
    - Photographs (Box 227)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 227)
  - Council
    The Council was the predecessor of the Assembly of Delegates and the original popular legislative body of the Association. This subseries contains mainly minutes and reports.
    - Minutes and reports, 1914-1922 (Box 217)
    - Minutes and reports; Board of Trustees, 1919-1963 (Box 217)
    - Minutes and reports, 1932-1949 (Box 217)
    - Correspondence, 1941, 1946 (Box 217)
    - Minutes and reports, 1951-1958 (Box 217)
  - Assembly of Delegates
    The Assembly of Delegates is the predecessor of the Senate. This subseries mostly contains meeting minutes.
    - Meeting minutes, 1959-1971 (Box 217)
    - Correspondence and information, 1961-1967 (Box 217)
    - Meeting materials, 1966; 2 folders (Box 217)
    - Proceedings AHEA 58th Annual Meeting (2 copies), 1967 (Box 217)
    - Meeting materials, 1971-1974; 5 folders (Box 217)
    - Meeting materials, 1975-1979; 4 folders (Box 241)
    - Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 241)
    - Minutes, 1982 (Box 241)
    - Minutes, 1982 (Box 77)
    - Meeting materials, 1984-1994; 11 folders (Box 241)
    - Parliamentarian, circa 1930, circa 1950-1970 (Box 241)
    - AHEA Parliamentary Procedure (Box 241)
    - AHEA mission statement, 1983 (Box 227)
    - Reports, minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 227)
  - Senate
    The collection contains few records of the Senate, the current popular legislative body of the Association.
    - Motion forms, 1995-1997 (Box 227)
    - Minutes and motion cards, 1999 (Box 241)
  - Elections
    - Candidate information and ballots, 1930, 1945-1981, 1985-1989, 1992, 1995; 5 folders (Box 227)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1966 (Box 227)
  - Annual reports
    This subseries contains annual reports mostly from the 1970s onwards.
    - Department, Division, Committee, and Staff reports, 1947-1952 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1968-1970 (Box 241)
    - Reports of AHEA activities, annual reports, 1970-1974; 3 folders (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1973-1978 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1976-1978 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1978-1981 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1983-1984 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1996-1997, 1997-1998, 1999, 2001 (Box 241)
    - Annual reports, 1995, 2001-2004 (Box 77)
    - Annual Activities and Accomplishments, 2002, 2003, 2005 (Box 326, Folder 17)
  - Bylaws, 1909-1979, 1987-1990, 1998; 5 folders (Box 241)
  - Bylaws, 1980-1986, 1990-1991, 1993-1994, 2004 (Box 77)
  - Directories and policy handbooks
    This subseries contains governance directories, which detail the leadership structure of the Association, and policy manuals and handbooks.
    - Organization and program, circa 1920-1960 (Box 10)
    - AHEA Pictorial Organization Chart, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1980-1985 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1981-1985 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1990-1991 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory, 1997-1998; 2000-2001 (Box 10)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual, 2004-2005 (Box 31)
    - Policy and procedures manual, 2002-2003 (Box 242)
    - Policy and procedures manual, 2004 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual, 2003-2004 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 2002 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 2001 (Box 242)
    - Policy and procedures manual, 2001-2002 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 2000 (Box 242)
    - Strategic Plan, 1995-2000 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual, 1999 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual/bylaws, 1998 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual/bylaws, 1997 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/reports/bylaws, 1996 (Box 242)
    - Strategic Plan/policy and procedures manual, 1995; 2 folders (Box 242)
    - Governance directory/policy and procedures manual, 1994 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1993 (Box 242)
    - Policy manual, 1993 (Box 31)
    - Policy and Procedures Manual revisions, 1993 (Box 31)
    - Governance directory, 1992 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1989 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1990 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1988 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1987 (Box 242)
    - Policy and procedures manual, 1984 (Box 242)
    - AHEA officers and committees, state affiliate lists, 1953-1974 (Box 242)
    - Governance reference materials, circa 1960 (Box 242)
    - Priorities of the AHEA, 1977-1978 (Box 242)
    - Governance directory, 1986-1987 (Box 242)
    - Programs of Work, 1984-forward (Box 242)
    - Handbook of the AHEA, 1942 (Box 241)
    - Handbook of the AHEA, 1947 (Box 188)
    - AHEA Policies and Working Papers, 1955 (Box 188)
    - Policies with Related Procedures and Official Authorizations of the AHEA (Box 188)
    - Policy Handbook, 1957 (Box 188)
    - Policy Handbook, 1969-1970, 1972 (Box 188)
    - AHEA Policy, 6 folders (Box 188)
    - Policy Handbook, 1978, 1984 (Box 188)
    - Policy Handbook, 1986 (Box 188)
    - Administrative materials, circa 1980 (Box 188)
    - Policy and governance information, 2 folders (Box 188)
    - Policy and Procedures Manuals, 1997-1998, 1999-2000, 2000-2001 (Box 188)
    - AHEA Planning Books, 1973, 1975, 1976-1977 (Box 188)
    - AHEA Planning Guide, 1978-1980 (Box 188)
    - Options for Growth-AHEA Planning Guide, 1978-1980 (Box 246)
    - Program of Work recommendations/planning, 1982 (Box 246)
    - Strategic Plan, 1995-2000 (Box 246)